So far we've learned a few common ways to
到目前为止 我们已经学习了
formulate and solve a portfolio optimization problem.
设定和求解投资组合优化问题的几种常见方式
But there are a number of practical limitations to these methods.
但是在实际操作这些方法时有一定的局限性
First of all, mean returns are notoriously difficult to estimate accurately.
首先 预期收益率一直都很难准确估算
Past returns are frequently poor estimates of future returns.
使用过去的收益率经常不能准确地估算未来的收益率
To mitigate this problem,
为了避免这种问题
people frequently avoid estimating returns directly altogether.
人们经常避免直接估算收益率
We've already introduced one possible solution which is to simply minimize
我们已经介绍了一种可能的方法
the difference between your portfolio weights and another set of target weights.
即最小化投资组合权重与目标权重之间的差异
Another technique is to use an alternative quantity thought to be predictive
另一种技巧是使用对预期收益率有较好预测能力的替代量
of future returns as a substitute for actual returns value estimates.
来替换实际收益率估算值
We're going to talk more about these methods in a future lesson.
我们将在后面的课程中详细讲解这些方法
There are also problems inherent to the estimation of portfolio variance.
投资组合方差估算本身也存在问题
The first is that variants may not be a good enough measure of risk.
第一个问题是方差可能无法准确地衡量风险
This is the theme that might come up whenever you rely upon variants to estimate risk.
每当你使用方差衡量风险时 都可能会遇到这种问题
To understand what I mean,
为了理解我的意思
think about the distribution of log returns.
请思考下对数收益率的分布
If the distribution has a different shape on the left side and on the right,
如果分布图的左侧和右侧形状不一样
this means there's a different probability of getting
那么获得很高的正收益率的概率
very high positive returns than getting very high negative returns,
与获得很高的负收益率的概率不一样
but mean and standard deviation won't tell you about this asymmetry.
但是均值和标准差并不能体现这种不对称性
For example, these two distributions have the same mean and the same standard deviation,
例如 这两个分布图的均值和标准差一样
but obviously very different shapes.
但明显形状差别很大
As a quantitative trader,
作为量化分析师
you really care about the shape of that negative tail because that part of
你对负尾部很关心
the distribution tells you how likely you are to get large negative returns.
因为这部分会告诉你获得很大的负收益率的概率是多少
As a workaround for this,
一种解决方法是
you can formulate your optimization problem using alternative measures of risk,
使用其他风险衡量指标构建优化问题
some of which we'll discuss in future lessons.
我们将在后面的课程中讨论某些风险衡量方法
Furthermore, the need to estimate an n by n covariance matrix,
此外 我们需要估算 n x n 方差矩阵
where n is the number of assets in your portfolio,
n 表示投资组合中的资产数量
means the problem size grows very quickly as the number of
当资产数量增大时 这个矩阵就变得很大
assets increases and the matrix becomes very large.
问题规模很快就变大
Estimating large numbers of parameters introduces
估算大量参数会导致
the possibility of aggregating many estimation errors.
很多估算误差累积起来
When the number of stocks n is of the same order of magnitude
当股票数量 n 的数量级与
as the number of historical return data points per stock t,
每支股票 t 的历史收益率数据点数量一样时
the total number of parameters to estimate in the covariance matrix is of
协方差矩阵中的参数总数数量级将与
the same order as the total size of the dataset, which is problematic.
数据集的总大小一样 这种情况很有问题
The need for a covariance matrix also means that we need to have
计算协方差矩阵需要
a long enough historical stock price dataset
足够长的历史股价数据集
to produce reliable estimates of covariances.
才能产生可靠的协方差估算值
For example, estimating a covariance matrix of
例如 估算 50 个资产的协方差矩阵
50 assets requires at least five years of daily data.
需要至少五年的每日数据
If there are not enough daily return data,
如果没有足够多的每日收益率数据
estimates of variances and covariances will not be accurate.
那么方差和协方差估算值将不准确
But in fact any estimate is noisy.
但实际上 任何估算值都有噪点
How do you handle noise?
如何处理噪点？
Well, instead of using raw values of quantities like means,
与其使用均值等原始值
you can utilize their ranks so that you only keep track of their relative magnitude.
你可以利用这些值的排名 这样只需跟踪相对大小
You can also simply include a term in the objective function to penalize turnover.
还可以在目标函数中添加一个惩罚周转率的项
This means that by default you are less likely to trade,
这样的话 默认情况下你就不太可能会交易
therefore your results will be less reactive to noise.
所以结果对噪点的敏感性更小
Finally, there's a method called robust optimization
最后还有一个方法叫鲁棒优化
which takes into account confidence intervals of estimates.
它会考虑估算的置信区间
Another issue which we discussed when we mentioned rebalancing is
另一个问题我们在讨论再平衡时提到过
that portfolio optimization is typically done
我们通常使用某个时期的一段数据
using a chunk of data from some time period,
再平衡投资组合优化问题
but then needs to be performed again as time passes and things change.
但是随着时间的推移和事物的变化 需要重新再平衡
In other words, the optimized weights are really only valid as long
也就是说 只有传入的参数准确时
as the estimates of the parameters fed into the problem are accurate.
优化的权重才有效
There's no built-in way to account for change over time.
没有什么固有的方法可以把估算值随着时间的变化考虑在内
But the changing nature of the stock market may
但是股市的变化性
lead to conflicting predictions over different time horizons.
可能会导致不同时间范围的预测有冲突
For example, what if your analysis tells you that
例如 分析师告诉你
a return over one day horizon will be positive,
一天的收益率为正
but over a one month horizon it will be negative?
但是一个月的收益率为负
In a single period optimization framework,
在单个优化时间范围内
it's not clear how to account for
我们不知道如何考虑不同的时间范围
the different timescales while taking into account the conflicting predictions.
或考虑有冲突的预测值
One approach to account for the changing nature of the stock market over time
在优化过程中考虑股市随时间推移而变化
as part of optimization is called multi-period optimization.
这个特性的一种方法是采用多期优化
In essence, this involves modeling a plan for trading over
这个方法会利用
the next several periods of time using
当前最有用的信息
the best information available at the current time,
构建一个包含未来多个时期的交易计划模型
and optimizing over this series of
并且针对这些未来交易进行优化
future trades but only ever executing the trades for the first period.
但只执行第一个时期的交易
This basically amounts to a planning exercise,
相当于做出规划
the idea is simply to try to ensure that we don't place
确保目前执行的交易
any traits now that will put us in a bad position in the future.
不会导致未来的业绩很差
In the example I just mentioned,
在刚刚提到的示例中
where we have a prediction that returns over one day will be positive,
我们预测一天的收益率为正
returns over one month will be negative,
一个月的收益率为负
we can see intuitively that it makes sense to go
所以很明显如果交易成本很低
long and short to take advantage of these predictions,
则先做多然后做空 以利用这些预测结果
if transaction costs are low but to refrain from trading if transaction costs are high.
但是如果交易成本很高 则不执行交易
If transaction costs are high,
如果交易成本很高的话
we may waste more money making trades than we could
按照正负收益率的预测结果进行交易
gain by following the predictions of positive and negative returns.
可能会损失更多的资金
A multi-period optimization analysis that includes
包含交易成本的多期优化分析
transaction costs would provide an optimal solution to this problem.
可以为这种问题提供最佳解
Another difficulty of portfolio optimization is
投资组合优化的另一个难题是
the ambiguity about how to deal with transaction costs.
不知道如何处理交易成本
Every time we make trades to rebalance the portfolio,
每次进行交易以再平衡投资组合时
we incur trading costs.
都会产生交易成本
But in general, they're difficult to precisely model.
但通常很难准确对这些成本建模
In order to account for them,
为了考虑这些成本
we model them as being proportional to turn over,
我们会假定成本与周转率成比例
the sum total of changes and portfolio weights.
即变化和投资组合权重的总和
But you can also include measures of turnover in the optimization problem formulation,
但是也可以在设定优化问题时包含周转率测量项
either as a constraint,
将周转率作为约束条件
or as a term to minimize in the objective function.
或作为目标函数中要最小化的项
To address some of these weaknesses,
为了避免这些不足之处
factor-based models of risk are often seen as more
通常我们会使用更实用的风险因子模型
practical but if this discussion seem rather abstract to you, just hang on.
如果这部分内容听起来很抽象的话 别担心
Many of these topics will be elaborated upon in a future lesson.
后面的课程会详细讲解这些知识的